Okay, this is I usually use this for my
好的，这是我平时用来装我土壤的
soil when I'm potting up or I used to.
我在换盆时通常使用的，或者以前使用的。
Um, but I want to try something
嗯，但我想在这里尝试一些不同的东西。
different with it down here. Uh, this is
嗯，这是我种植种子的地方。也是我的蚯蚓所在的地方。
where I grow my seeds. It's where my
嗯，所以希望这周晚些时候我们能去那里看看。
worms are. Um, so hopefully later this
嗯，但现在外面又冷了。冬天又回来了，至少还要持续几天。
week we can get to that. Um, but it's
嗯，我本该这周在这里整理我的种植工作。
cold outside again. Winter has returned
所以我想带你们来这里，给你们看看我的种植情况。
uh for at least a few days. Um, and I'm
并不是所有东西都进展顺利。有些是。
supposed to be spending my week down
嗯，但嗯，是的，今年我已经犯了一些错误。
here catching up on my seating. So, I
好的，那么首先，我想看看我几周前做的插穗。
thought I'd take you down here, show you
嗯，说实话，我对它们现在的样子有点失望。
where I'm at, what things are looking
这完全是我的错。
like. It's not all going well. Some is.
我盖上了盖子，把它们放在了灯光下，和之前做的一模一样。
Um, but uh, yeah, I do have a few
就像第一批我做的，嗯，它们看起来很棒。它们都
mistakes already this year. Okay, so
first up, I thought we would look at the
cutings I did a couple weeks ago and um,
to be honest, I'm kind of bummed uh,
with how they're looking. And this is
totally my fault. Um,
I put the lid on, I put them under
lights, the same thing I did to the
round before, and like the first batch I
did, um, they look great. They're all
potted up. Um, they just rooted after a
上盆了。嗯，它们几周后就生根了。所以，成功了。所以，我没太在意。我把这个批次盖着盖子放在了灯下，
few weeks. So, success. So, I didn't
但放在了不同的架子上，这个就在灯正对着的地方。我想那里水分太多再加上灯的热量，就太潮湿了。所以，是的，很多都像长霉一样。
really think much of it. I put this um
嗯，叶子变褐了。嗯，它们在枯死。有些完全死了，腐烂了。嗯，但是的，一旦我发现这样了，我就把它移到了这组灯下。
batch with the lid on under the lights,
嗯，我打开了通风口，让它有更多气流。嗯，这不是完全的损失。比如我想有些它们啊，嗯，看这个。嗯，我们有根了。所以，
but I put it on a different shelf and
不是说我肯定有些，所以没事。还有这边的菊花，嗯，它们也在生根。我想菊花生根速度很快，可能更能忍受恶劣条件。所以，也许
this it was right against the lights. I
think with the amount of moisture in
there and then the heat from the lights,
it was just too much. So, yeah, a lot of
them kind of show like a fungus. Uh the
the leaves are turning brown. Um they're
dying. Some full out just died and
rotted. Um, but yeah, so once I realized
that was happening, I moved it to this
set of lights. Um, I opened up the
vents, gave it a little bit more
airflow. Um, and it's not a total loss.
Like I think some of them Oh, like Yeah,
look at this. Um, we have roots. So,
it's not like I definitely have some, so
it's fine. And the chrysanthemums at
this end, uh, yeah, they're showing
roots, too. I think chrysanthemums just
root a lot quicker and probably can
tolerate worse conditions. So, maybe
I'll just get this out of here and pot
我先把这些移出来，再栽上我所能种的。嗯，哦，是的。看看这些根。
up what I can. And um Oh, yeah. Look at
不管怎样，学到了教训。嗯，你要注意保持土壤湿度适中，不过分潮湿，也不过分干燥，不要离灯光太近。
more roots.
所以，实际上我种下的植物并不多。
Anyways, lesson learned. Uh you have to
我想往年我可能会种多一点，但我在尝试不要过早地过分种植。
uh keep an eye not too wet, uh not too
嗯，这一边是我的插穗。
dry, not too close to the lights.
顶部是上个月我播种的多年生鬼针草。嗯，它长得很好。非常满意。
So, I don't actually have a lot seated.
然后我还有这些桉树苗，放在这个架子上。我发现它们看起来还行，但它们太小了，我很难照料好，要么是浇水过多，要么是浇水过少，或者施肥过多。
I think other years I might have a bit
我总是有些会死掉，比如它们的叶子会干枯，嗯，是的，这不总是意味着它们会死，但在这个阶段，我
more seated, but I'm trying to uh not be
over agressive with seating too early
on. Um, so this side here is my cutings.
At the top is the perennial scabiosa
that I seeded a month ago. Um, it is
looking great. So, super happy with
that. And then I have my eucalyptus
babies um on this shelf, too. I do find
um they they look okay. They are I find
I have difficulty when they're so little
um either overwatering them or
underwatering them or giving them too
much fertilizer. And I always lose some
to like I'm not exactly sure their
leaves kind of shrivel up and um yeah,
it doesn't always mean that they're
going to die, but they at this stage I
feel like it's a delicate uh time. So
感觉现在是个比较微妙的时间。所以
they look okay. I think they look okay.
它们看起来还不错。我觉得它们挺好的。
Uh hopefully in the next few weeks they
希望在未来几周内它们
really take off and we're past this
能真正生长起来，我们就能度过这个
sensitive stage.
敏感阶段。
Okay, so most of what's in the basement
好的，所以现在地下室里
right now is lizanthis. Um I have my
大部分是lizenthis。嗯，我已经完成了
first three rounds seated. So, I started
前三批的种植。所以，我于一月中旬
with my orange trays uh mid January. Um
开始用我的橙色托盘种植。嗯
then I did all my green trays. Um I
然后我用所有的绿色托盘。嗯
filled up my pink trays for my third
我用粉色托盘完成了第三批种植。而
round. And this week I need to do my
这周我需要完成第四批种植。所以，嗯
fourth round. So, um yeah, I think it's
我觉得现在看起来很不错。对前几批
looking pretty good. Pretty happy with
的生长我很满意。嗯，考虑到当你看到
the growth um for the first few um
刚刚被挖开的托盘时，它们有多小，然后
considering when you see a fresh tray
我来看我的橙色托盘，我想，“哦，是的，
that's just uh uncovered how tiny they
我们有生长。”所以，并非所有种子都
are and then I come and look at my
都很好地发芽。我正在用掉所有旧的种子，而我
orange trays and I think, "Oh, yes, we
有些种子是四年前存的。嗯。所以那
have growth." So, not all of them have
些种子发芽不太好，但对于大多数东西
germinated great. I'm trying to use up
我都有相当不错的发芽率。
all my old seed and I had some seed that
was um four years old. Yeah. So that did
not germinate well, but for most things
I have fairly good germination rates.
Yeah. And so this is the first year that
嗯。所以这是我头一年
I um seeded my lizanths by putting them
通过在压出土壤块之前
into the soil blocks before I pushed the
将种子放入土壤块中来
soil blocks out. And um my goal was to
播种生菜。嗯。我的目标
not have to break off any of the pellets
是让它们发芽后不用
after they germinated or I know a lot of
剥离任何颗粒。我知道
people spray their trays down and I've
很多人会喷洒育苗盘，
never liked spraying. I get a lot more
我一直不喜欢喷洒。
algae and I just find it very time
这样会滋生很多藻类，
consuming. So I'm not a mister with a
而且我觉得非常费时。
spray bottle on my seedlings. Um but I
所以我从不使用喷雾瓶
have to say that I'm very happy. There's
来喷洒幼苗。嗯。但
very few Yeah. that look like this where
我必须说我很满意。
I still have to break the pallet. Like I
很少有像这样需要
think that's the um Yeah. I just I just
剥离颗粒的。嗯。我
don't have to do that this year where
只是今年不用做这个，
other years I was breaking off a lot
而往年我发芽后要
more pellets uh after germination.
剥离很多颗粒。嗯。
Okay, so the worms and me are feeling a
好的，所以蚯蚓和我
little squished.
都感觉有点挤。
Um, I I I don't know. I keep a container
嗯，我不知道。我总在
by my kitchen. I fill it up with food
厨房边放个容器，
scraps and stuff that I know that the
填满我知道蚯蚓会吃
worms will eat. And I I have quite a
的食物残渣之类的。
bit. I feel like more food than I have
我有不少。感觉食物比
room to feed. And I can always use more
有足够的空间喂食。而且我总需要更多
castings. So, I don't think I want
铸件。所以，我不太想要
another worm tower cuz I I actually
另一个蚯蚓塔，因为我其实
think um I want to try this. I think
觉得嗯，我想试试这个。我认为
this might be easier to feed into and
这个可能更容易喂食进去，和
it's just more space. Um, so what I'm
它就是更多空间。嗯，所以我要
going to try and do with this blue bin
尝试用这个蓝色箱子
is make a wedge system uh worm farm
做一个楔形系统蚯蚓农场
here. So I'll still have the two towers.
在这里。所以我还是会有两个塔。
Um, but I can give them a little bit
嗯，但我可以给他们一点
more time to process the food without
更多时间来处理食物，而不
jamming more in there. And then I'll
是再塞进去更多。然后我还会
also have uh this uh little farm here.
也有这个，这个小农场在这里。
So the idea with a wedge system is that
楔形系统的想法是，你把你的
you put your uh worm castings, more
蚯蚓堆肥，更多
finished uh compost at one end. So this
完成的堆肥放在一端。所以这
is where I dumped the tray from my
是我倒掉我塔的托盘的地方。所以
tower. So, there's worms in here. Um,
这里有很多蚯蚓。嗯，
and there's lots for them to still
而且还有很多可以继续
finish. And then you cover that with
完成。然后你用床铺覆盖它。所以
bedding. So, I am using leaves and I
我正在用叶子，我有纸板和其他
have cardboard and other stuff to put
东西来放。然后它就是系统中的
in. And then it's kind of uh the next
下一个楔形。然后我会
wedge in the system. And then I will
喂食到床铺区域。嗯，和
feed into the bedding area. Um, and the
next time I will put in some more
下次我会再放多一些
bedding and feed into there. And
床垫和饲料进去。而且
everything from this far end will slowly
这头的东西会慢慢
finish and the worms will like the idea
完成，而蚯蚓会喜欢这个想法
is that they'll move across and keep
就是它们会移动过来并继续
eating their way down. So, I think it'll
吃着往下走。所以，我认为
be easier for me to quickly feed in
我可以更容易地快速在这里喂食
here. That's the idea. And then also
这就是想法。而且也
easier for me to find some finished uh
更容易让我找到一些完成的
worm castings that that end without
蚯蚓堆肥，而不用
having to pull apart my whole tower. So,
拆开我的整个塔。所以，
I don't mind my towers. I just I just
我不介意我的塔。我只是
want to try something new and I just
想尝试一些新东西，我
need more space for worms so I can grow
只需要更多空间给蚯蚓，这样我
more worms and ideally get more
就能养更多蚯蚓，理想情况下
castings. Okay, I found this like
获得更多堆肥。好的，我在地下室
thicker sheet of plastic down here in
找到了一张更厚的塑料片。我要
the basement. I'm going to use that as
用它当盖子，因为我不想让它
my lid because I don't want to dry out.
干燥。所以，如果现在家里
So, if there's nothing on top with the
顶部没有东西，而且有干燥的空气，
dry air in the house right now, um I
我要防止这种情况。而且我也
want to prevent that. And then I also
喜欢我临时搭建的地方。嗯
like my makeshift uh place here. Um I
我放了一些木头下来防止它
put some wood down to stop it from
滚动，以防万一。嗯，而且它就是
rolling just in case. Um and it's
slightly sloped. So if it's too wet, cuz
稍微倾斜。所以如果太湿，因为
I do tend to feed uh a lot of stuff that
我倾向于喂很多东西，它们
has a lot of water in it. Um that will
含水量很大。嗯，这些水会
drain to this end. So I can keep an eye
排到这一端。这样我就能观察
on if it's too dry or too wet. If it
它是太干还是太湿。如果它
ends up being too dry, I can always add
结果太干，我总可以再加
more moisture. But I don't The problem
一些水分。但问题是制作视频
with making videos is that um I think if
是因为嗯，如果我没有做，
I didn't, my family probably wouldn't
我的家人可能就不会意识到
realize what I'm doing down here. Um but
我在这里做什么。嗯，但现在他们
now they're might see that I've put a
也许会看到我放了一个
barrel of worms.
蛇皮桶。
And I don't know what they're going to
但我不知道他们会怎么想，但
think, but I think this is super cool.
我想这太酷了。我祈祷这次
And I'm crossing my fingers that I have
能成功。
success with this.
所以当我看到托盘时，它通常
So when I see the tray, it usually comes
放在这个房间这一侧的架子上。
on this shelf at this side of the room.
所以嗯，这些蓝色托盘是这周的
So uh these blue trays are this week's
莴苣。所以我在处理蓝色托盘。
round of lizanths. So I'm working on the
我还没完成。所以这个最后的
blue. I'm not quite done. So this last
粉色托盘是两周前的，其他的
pink was from two weeks ago and the rest
都移到那边了。但这一个我
of them have all moved over there. But
等了一段时间。我想这是我做的
this one I'm waiting a little bit longer
最后一个。嗯
on. I think it's the last one I did. Um
these shorter trays I'm using just for
我现在用的这些较短的托盘只是用来放
the random stuff. So, I have um so far
一些零碎的东西。所以，到目前为止
Crespedia,
有Crespedia，
uh uh FeverFW, Dianthis, and a few snapd
呃呃 FeverFW、Dianthis，还有几个snapd
dragons. So, I'm going to hopefully do
拖龙。所以，我希望能在这个周末和下个
more of that uh this weekend and next
周多做些这样的东西，还有一些其他
week, and some of the other cool annuals
漂亮的年度植物或多年生植物。我得翻
or perennials. I got to dig through my
翻我的种子盒看看有什么。而且在这里，
seed box and see what I have. And down
我有一些空间这个周末可以再放一些
here, I have some space to get some more
托盘。呃，底部是我在冰箱里拿出来的
trays in this weekend. Um the bottom are
飞燕草。呃，所以我把它们放进了冰箱，
the delinium that I took out of the
大概是一月中旬，我超级兴奋现在
fridge. Uh, so I put them in the fridge,
突然冒出来的所有这些。呃，是的，它们
I don't know, mid January, and I'm super
看起来很棒。所以，这太酷了，因为
excited about all of them that have
飞燕草已经成为我最喜欢种植的东西。
popped up now. Uh, yeah, they're looking
然后这是呃
great. So, that's super cool cuz
我种下的第一批球茎，也就是dia球茎。
delphinium has become a new favorite
呃，是的，我想我得尽快开始剪枝了。
thing for me to grow. And then this is
所以，我们看看这些呃，如果今年我
the uh
有没有剪枝的好运气。好吧，
the first few tubers uh dia tubers I
potted up. And yeah, I think I'm going
to have to start taking uh cutings soon.
So, we'll see if these uh if I have any
luck with these cutings this year. Okay,
so um I just counted. I think I have
所以我数了一下，我觉得这里还能再种38棵树。嗯
room for 38 more trees down here. Uh
这太好了。应该能让我忙活好几个星期了。然后
which is super. That should keep me busy
嗯，是的，我觉得离春天可能还剩不到20天了，但有些
for the next uh couple weeks. And then
这些东西可以开始转移到车库了，然后嗯，一个月
um yeah, I think we're only like maybe
可能会拿到外面的车库里。所以，嗯，我觉得这样挺好的。嗯
less than 20 days until spring, but some
虽然现在托盘的数量比我通常2月份有的要少，但我
of this stuff can start transitioning to
对现在的状况很满意，而且我今年在种植上很用心，所以我不打算
the garage and then yeah, in a month
种那些我可能不需要或者根本卖不掉的东西。所以，我
possibly out uh to the wagon outside.
还没让任何一个托盘干透。通常情况下，我总会在某个时候
So, um yeah, I think it looks good. Uh
因为没浇水而毁掉一两个托盘。嗯 哦，但
even though there's like less uh trays
实际上我正在看这个托盘，它还没干透。但这是个错误。
than I normally have for February, I'm
这是我今年犯的第一个错误，就是嗯，这是桉树，我把它种了。
I'm happy with where I'm at and I'm
我贴上了标签
trying to be very intentional with what
I'm seating this year so I don't grow
things that maybe I don't need to or um
that I won't possibly sell. So, and I
haven't I haven't let a tray dry out
yet. Usually, at some point, I kill a
tray or two by not watering. Um Oh, but
actually I'm looking at this tray. It's
not dried out. But this is one mistake.
This was the very first mistake I made
this year is that um it's eucalyptus and
I seated it. I put the uh the label in
and then I realized there was um already
然后我意识到托盘里已经有一个标签了
a label in the tray. So I had grabbed a
所以我拿了一个我以为空的托盘
tray that I thought was empty and I
然后在上面种了两株不同的桉树品种
double seated it with two varieties
所以
different varieties of eucalyptus. So
这里有点拥挤。它们看起来
it's a little bit crowded. They look
还不错。我会确保这个春天在田里
okay. I'll just make sure I give them
给它们留出更多空间。
extra space uh in the field this spring.
所以是的，这是二月底我的种植区。
So yeah, that's uh my seating room for
谢谢你们来参加我这里的小参观。
the end of February. Uh thank you for
谢谢观看、订阅、点赞和成为会员。
coming on my little tour down here. And
我真的非常感谢。
uh thank you for watching and
下次再见。
subscribing and liking and becoming
members, all of that. I really
appreciate it. And I'll see you again
next time.